Odd ducks welcome.
Migration is a family, comedy, adventure film directed by Benjamin Renner.
After a migrating duck family alights on their pond with thrilling tales of far-flung places, the Mallard
family embarks on a family road trip, from New England, to New York City, to tropical Jamaica.
Mack Mallard (voice), played by Kumail Nanjiani.
Pam Mallard (voice), played by Elizabeth Banks.
Dax Mallard (voice), played by Caspar Jennings.
Gwen Mallard (voice), played by Tresi Gazal.
Chump (voice), played by Awkwafina.
Erin (voice), played by Carol Kane.
Migration is a 2023 American animated adventure comedy film
directed by Benjamin Renner and written by Mike White.
Produced by Illumination and distributed by Universal Pictures, the film stars the voices of
Kumail Nanjiani, Elizabeth Banks, Keegan-Michael Key, Awkwafina, and Danny DeVito.
The story follows a family of mallards who try to convince their overprotective father to go on a vacation
of a lifetime and attempt to migrate from New England, through New York City, to Jamaica.
Illumination announced Migration in February 2022, with Renner and
White attached as director and writer, respectively.
Renner, who had previously helmed traditionally animated films, including
Ernest & Celestine (2012) and The Big Bad Fox and Other Tales...
(2017), was tasked with adapting his simple drawing
style for a computer-animated film.
In hiring Renner, studio head and producer Chris Meledandri sought to focus on a
filmmaker's vision for the project in comparison with Illumination's recent films.
John Powell composed the score, marking his second collaboration
with Illumination following The Lorax (2012).
Migration premiered at the VIEW Conference in Turin, Italy, on October 19, 2023,
and was theatrically released in the United States on December 22.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and
grossed $300.5 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of duck, villain, migration, flight, anthropomorphism.
The tone is lighthearted and intense.